#大家好 今天我們摘點這個木槿花回去吃啊
Hi everyone! Today we'll pick some rose mallow back home for,
#回去用來做那個晚上的菜
for our dinner.
#家裡沒菜吃啦
We are running out of food.
#肉又不捨得吃
We don't wanna spend to much on meat.
#竹鼠又不捨得吃啦 現在
And even bamboo rats are too luxurious for us now.
#我們摘一點這個木槿花
Let's pick some rose mallow here,
#用
to,
#裹點那個 裹點那個麵粉啊
to fry it after dipping,
#用油來煎
and then panfry in oil
#應該很好吃 上次我們是
It should be tasty. Last time we,
#是 是種炒的
we were, like, stir-fried it.
#這次我們要
This time we
#煎著
fry.
#把它煎啦
Fry it.
#哈哈
Ha ha
#我們這邊叫雞肉花
This is called "chicken flower" here.
#因為吃起來 有點雞肉的味道
It's because it has a light chicken flavour,
#就叫雞肉花
so it is called "chicken flower".
#你看 這些都是很漂亮的哦
See? These are all very pretty.
#樹上都有花
There are flowers all over the tree.
#你看 這個
See? This...
#這個還沒開苞的這個就不要去 不要去動啦
this has not yet blossomed. We have better leave it, leave it alone.
#下次長 下次長出來 長出來 有需要的人就可以摘
Next time when it gro...when it, when it blossoms. Those who need it can take it.
#剛好
Just now,
#把我老弟也過來一起摘
my little brother is here to pick with me.
#你看 它這個花都收回去啦
See? This flower shrinks.
#是不是太陽太熱啦
Is it because the sun is too strong?
#我們就吃這個花瓣
The edible part is the petals.
#收回去了我也不放過你 我也把你摘回去
Don't think I'll forgo you just because you're closed. I'll take it back home.
#多摘一點 太少啦
Let's pick some more, there's not enough.
#你看 這個都 曬得把它收回去啦
See? This is... The sun is too strong that they've all shrunk.
等下太陽下山的時候它又收 又張開
They'll shr...blossom again after sunset.
#太聰明啦 這個花
The flowers are too clever.
#但是騙不過我的眼睛
But my eyes are smarter.
#把你們通通[SIC]摘掉
You are all mine now.
#摘了一個
I got one!
#哇 那有蕉芋花
Wa! There are Indian shots.
#這還有 鑽進去
Sneak inside, there are some.
#鑽進去
Sneak inside.
#誒 全都掉啦
Eh? All are dropped.
#嗯 摘了那麼一點點 夠啦
Um! Just a little bit. But it's enough.
#我們去它花瓣
We'll pick the petals,
#然后再
and then...
#再用油来煎一下
Then fry in oil.
#没什么味道
Can't smell anything,
#要煎 煎好啦 才有味道的
not, not until we have it fried.
#我们拿回去煎一下
We'll fry it at home.
#把这个花 把这个蒂子取掉它
The flower, I mean the stalk, needs to be removed.
#把这个一片一片的花瓣 摘下来
And then we can pick the petals, piece by piece.
#这个就不好的 这个芯
This pistil/stamen needs to be thrown away.
#我们去把这个洗一下
We'll wash it first.
#嗯 是有点鸡肉味哦
Um, there is really a scent of chicken.
#淡淡的 不是很浓
It's a very light one, not strong.
#洗一下
Wash it.
#洗好啦
It's alright now.
#我们加点盐 加点面粉
We'll put some salt, and some flour,
#就这样
and then,
#煎来吃
fry it.
#很香
Smells good.
#加点盐
Some salt
#不够
Not enough
#多加点
More!
#最近口味比较重
I've liked a stronger taste recently.
#这样拌一下 这样 鸡肉花里面就有盐啦
Mix it well, then, then the salt will be absorbed into the chicken flower.
#加点这个 我们这边的叫蕉芋粉
Some... it is called "jiao yu fen" (Indian shots root starch) here.
#你看 怎么这样子的
See? What's happened?
#加点酱油
Some soy sauce.
#可以啦
Okay!
#好吃的哦
It's tasty.
#啊
Ah?
#看上去就靓
It looks beautiful.
#像现在煎了它 好漂亮的哦
Now I am frying it. It's pretty.
#可以哦
It's not bad.
#熟啦
It's done.
#这个很快的
It doesn't take too long.
#啊 好香哦
Oh! It smells good.
#出去尝一下
Let me have a try.
#一地都是狗
The dogs are every where.
挡路啦 看到没有
See? You are blocking my way.
#尝一下
Have a try!
#味道不错哦
The taste is not bad.
比上次炒的好吃多啦
It's much better than last time when we had it stir-fried.
#这个味道好像
The taste is like,
#有点像鸡肉味
it has a light chicken flavour,
#但是又不像
but, not really.
#你看 里面就有点滑滑的
See? It's mucous inside.
#也有点那个鸡肉的味道
And there is a, a flavour of chicken.
#估计以前
I think in the past...
#这个 我们这边叫鸡肉花 可能就这样来的
I mean, perhaps that's why we call it "chicken flower" here.
#味道还可以哦
The taste is not bad.
#好啦 今天的视频就到这里啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#这个留到晚上 晚上来吃
I'll leave it, leave for dinner as
#下饭
side dish.
#放了有点咸 (這句完全不知謂何，我估他是想說"放了太多鹽，有點咸"但中間刪略了，所以翻譯同樣處理)
With the it's salty.